pressbox.co.uk 2003-04-08

# pressbox - uk press - release distribution - press store - copywriting services

Introduction

Pressbox is a service maintained by Midas Internet Limited ("MIDAS"). 

MIDAS are registered with the Data Protection Act 1998.

MIDAS complies with the eight Data Protection Principles.

In summary they require that data shall be:

1\. fairly and lawfully processed

2\. processed for limited purposes

3\. adequate, relevant and not excessive

4\. accurate

5\. not kept longer than necessary

6\. processed in accordance with the data subjects' rights

7\. secure

8\. not transferred to countries outside the EEA without adequate protection.

MIDAS is committed to responsible management of consumer data. We comply with all rules, both ethical and legal, with respect to the use of consumer information obtained by us and we adhere strictly to all industry guidelines at all times. We undertake to continuously monitor our management of the use and security of consumer information to uphold your rights. 

This statement outlines the type of information we collect and store, our usage policy, and whom to contact with questions or concerns. Midas Internet Limited owns and operates this Web site. We serve online advertisements to users of Web sites operated by clients signed to our Company. 

Personal Data

On www.pressbox.co.uk, MIDAS will not collect any personally-identifiable information about you (name, address, telephone number, email address) unless you provide it to us voluntarily. If you do not want your personal information collected, please do not submit it. 

Once collected, such data will be held within the European Union and the European Economic Area and will only be used for the specific purpose for which it was sought and to which you consented. It will not be used for any other purpose whatsoever. Any personal data we hold on you will be deleted or updated upon request and any inaccurate or misleading data held will be changed or deleted upon your request. If you no longer wish to receive the information for which your data was collected, or should you wish your data to be deleted or amended for any reason, please let us know by contacting us at the email address or telephone number listed at the bottom of this Statement.

Any data supplied by you will be kept secure in accordance with the requirements of our data protection licence and with the directions of the Data Protection Commissioner through whom this licence is held.

Details of the data we hold on you will be provided on request although we reserve the right to charge the relevant statutory disclosure fee (where appropriate). Any request of this nature should be directed to the e-mail address shown at the bottom of this notice.

Non-personally Identifiable Information Collected Automatically

For each visitor to www.pressbox.co.uk, our Web server automatically recognizes your domain, the type of Internet browser you are using, the type of computer operating system you are using, and the domain name of the Web site from which you linked to our site. This non-personally identifiable information is collected automatically, used for internal review, then discarded. 

Consumers' Privacy Rights

MIDAS holds the consumer relationship in the highest regard and pledges: 

To ensure that consumers have the ultimate right to control dissemination of their personal information. We support the self-regulation efforts of the direct marketing industry and believe this action is the best way to protect consumer privacy. We support legislation and regulatory efforts, which introduce fair, workable guidelines that protect the privacy of consumers. We will work to ensure that any such guidelines are consistent with and complement established self-regulatory measures, and that they allow the consumer to continue receiving the benefits that sophisticated marketing techniques can provide.

To comply with all relevant legislation at all times and to implement such legislation as required.

To monitor privacy issues and assure that any changes in legislation or industry standards regarding privacy issues are reflected in our Privacy Policy. We are in constant contact with our client Web sites to identify and resolve misunderstandings about the law, industry standards or our Privacy Policy and to ensure their compliance with all self-regulatory and legislative obligations relating to the use of consumer data.

To work with recognised trade associations and organizations that support consumer privacy. We actively participate in the efforts of Europe's Direct Marketing Industry to establish industry guidelines that safeguard the individual right to privacy.

To provide services that benefit both consumers and marketers. Consumers benefit from our services through the realisation of lower prices that result from the marketers' more efficient communications approach. In addition, consumers realise savings in time and expense by being able to shop via the Internet. Marketers can better tailor their products and services to meet the needs of their customers with our assistance. Further, they can refine their promotional efforts to target only those customers for whose benefit the products have been produced.

Cookies

Note that in some areas of the site we use "cookies". A cookie is a software application that enables a site to customise its services to the interests of the user. This is achieved by tracking the user's navigation of the site and storing that information on the user's hard drive. For example, a cookie can be used to store registration information in an area of the site so that a user does not have to provide it on subsequent visits to that area. 

Cookies are used to better personalise the content, banners and promotions that you will see. We may use this information to research and understand how our user's habits are similar or different so that we can enhance your experience on our Web site. 

We may transfer your personal data for internal business purposes to locations outside the European Economic Area, some of which may have different data protection laws to the UK, or no data protection laws. 

You have a right to know about the personal information MIDAS holds about you. You also have a right to have your data corrected or deleted. Please e-mail questions or requests for more information about MIDAS's privacy policies and initiatives to admin@midasinternet.com. Anyone may request the removal of his or her name from MIDAS's marketing database by sending an e-mail to admin@midasinternet.com. You must provide your name, complete street address, city, country, post code and e-mail address. Any data we hold on you will be deleted from our existing files upon receipt of such notice. If you have any queries about this Privacy Statement or wish to resume receiving information which you may have previously opted out from receiving, please contact us via info@midasinternet.com or by telephone on 020 7388 7654 or write to us at 121 Parkway, Regents Park, London, NW1 7PS
